Matthew Lee

Phone <u>+64 22 010 6288</u> | Email <u>hello@matthewlee.co.nz</u> | Web <u>matthewlee.co.nz</u>

About Me

I am looking for a professional internship, in a software engineering role, to develop my knowledge and experience in the IT sector. Ideally, this role would be in web development however I also have a keen interest in software development and solution architecture. I am passionate about the tech industry and am always dedicated to the task at hand. I have excellent communication and time-management skills. This is evidenced by working in multiple groups at university and working in a team environment in retail for the past three years all while juggling assignments and extra-curricular activities. If I am not at my computer, you will likely find me walking the hills around Wellington, skiing on Mount Ruapehu or off travelling somewhere around New Zealand. Currently, I am a fourth-year software engineering student at Victoria University of Wellington looking to complete my degree in November 2018.

Technical Skills

Area	Tools	Skill Level	Experience
Design	Photoshop, InDesign, Bootstrap	Intermediate	Worked with these for projects throughout college and for personal use.
Programming Languages	C, C++, C#, Python, HAML, SASS, Node.js, PHP, SQL	Beginner	Learnt the basics in courses at university and through outside projects.
	HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Ruby on Rails	Intermediate	Developed websites/apps throughout college and university, as well as for a hobby.
	Java	Proficient	Three years of learning Java at University for projects and assignments.
Other	Git, Docker	Beginner	Used throughout university and work for various projects.

Past Projects

Advance Directives Application

March 2017 - October 2017

Myself and five other third year students are developing an Advance Directives Application for a client who is a paramedic with Wellington Free Ambulance. This project requires a vast amount of project management whilst also considering the legal and ethical obligations of users. For this project, I held the role of developer. The application is being developed using Rails.

Cheese Reviewer Application

July 2016

As part of the Microsoft Student Accelerator program I used Xamarin Forms and C# to develop a cross-platform mobile application. It utilised Microsoft's Azure Platform and Cognitive Services. The application allows a user to review cheeses, it then saves this information to an Easy Table where the user can view

previously rated cheeses. It is also connected to the Emotion API so a user can read their emotion regarding their feelings towards the cheese. It is available to view on GitHub here.

Music Collection Database October 2016

Using Ruby on Rails, I created a web based application to store details about a user's music collection. This involved managing and developing associated models, views and controllers. Languages and tools learnt for this project include HAML, SASS and Bootstrap. The application can be viewed on my GitHub.

Education

Official academic transcripts are available on request. An unofficial transcript is available on my website.

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2015 – November 2018

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours)

Achieved an A+ mark in most of my papers and currently have a GPA of A. My lowest mark in my first three years of University is an A-. Academic highlights include achieving an A+ in three out of four of my second-year papers and two A+ grades in my trimester one third year papers.

University of Surrey, Guildford, United Kingdom

September 2016 – February 2017

International Exchange, Computing

As part of the Victoria Abroad program, I was accepted to be a part of an exchange for a trimester to the University of Surrey. Surrey is consistently ranked in the top 10 universities in the UK and specialises in sciences and engineering. I achieved firsts in all modules I was enrolled in.

Achievements & Volunteer Work

Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) Prize

2017

The Wellington Network of the Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) sponsors this prize for engineering students enrolled at Victoria University. The prize will be for the best student in their third year.

Dean's List, Faculty of Engineering and Computer Science

2015, 2017

The Dean's List is a formal and published record of students who achieve academic excellence in their current year of study in an undergraduate degree programme.

Summer of Tech Hackfest

2017

I was one fifth of the "Weekend Artists" team, where we came first equal. We developed the "Artchive NZ" application which creates a new way to discover New Zealand art and the colour palettes within. It utilised the Digital NZ and Imagga APIs. The app can be viewed on GitHub here.

IPENZ

2017

Assisted the IPENZ Member Engagement Manager and Student Representative with a range of activities. These included their "Speed Interview" night, writing an article for the "StudentDirect" newsletter and putting on an afternoon tea for student members.

Onslow College Peer Support Leader

2014

Peer Support ensures students transitioning from intermediate can cope with college life. Peer Supporters are selected based on their skills in leadership, communication and cooperation, empathy and understanding and creativity and initiative.

Work Experience

Abletech Nov 2017 – Current

http://www.abletech.nz/

Intern – Trainee Technical Consultant

For this internship, I was part of Abletech's development team. I programmed mainly in Ruby on Rails helping maintain a variety of in-house and external client products.

Wisebuys on Dixon May 2013 – Nov 2017

http://www.wisebuys.nz

Sales Assistant

My tasks involve interacting with customers to ensure they have a pleasant retail experience. I am also responsible for opening/closing the store on certain weekends.

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2016 – June 2016

https://www.victoria.ac.nz/courses/engr/101/2016/offering?crn=15243

ENGR101 Tutor

My tasks included running labs, marking assignments/tests and making sure first year students knew the concepts and content being covered in this introductory engineering course.

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2016 – September 2016

https://www.victoria.ac.nz/courses/phys/122/2016/offering?crn=18194

PHYS122/SARC122 Sessional Assistant (Marker)

The PHYS122 and SARC122 courses involved marking weekly assignments where I reported directly to the course coordinator.

Referees

Referees available on request.